Curriculum Vitae

Md. Rezaul Islam

Mailing Address:

Apex Drug House

D. C. Road, West Bakalia (Mousumir Moor)

Chawkbazar Chittagong-4000

Cell: +880-1556-707000, +880-1972-433268

E-Mail: rezaul.islam@accountant.com



To secure an employment that enables me to portray competency in academic skills and to professionally utilize skills and talent in an excellent environment which will provide job satisfaction, economic security, opportunity of career growth and contribute to the development of the society in general.

Career Summary

Having 80 months above work experience in the Finance & Accounts arena. Of them, 11 months experience with one of the MNC in Bangladesh named Unilever (BD) Ltd, 29 months above experience with one of the famous Shipping Agency in Bangladesh named Haque & Sons Limited and the rest of months with national organizations in Bangladesh.

Key Skills Developed

Communication Skills: Native speaker of Bengali language. High level written and oral communication skills have been developed in English as a result of extensive research works, class lectures, and through interaction with people from different strata of the society.

Planning & Budgeting: Have proven skill of preparing plan of operation, work plan for short and long-term period, preparing budget for project, budget for different events.

Report Writing Skills: Have proven capacity in writing formal business report as well as short report due to the requirement of line of work.

Computer Skills: Proficient in using MS office package Fluent in English & Bengali typing and using internet for communication.

Employment History

1. Senior Accountant in ATS Group Ltd (January 2017 – Continuing)

ATS Group Limited.

Location: Chittagong Office

Address: 870, Sheikh Mujib Road, Dewanhat, Chittagong.

Department: Accounts & Finance Reporting to: Managing Director.



2 Assistant Accounts Officer (Vat) in Hague & Sons Limited (August 2014 – Dec 2016)

Haque& Sons Limited.

Location: Head Office

Address: Agrabad, Chittagong.

Department: Accounts & Finance

Reporting to: Assistant Accounts Manager (Head Office).

3. Accountant in AnB Pumps Limited (October 2012 – February 2014)

AnB Pumps Limited.

Location: Chittagong Region Office Address: Jubilee Road, Chittagong. Department: Accounts & Finance

Reporting to: Accounts Manager (Head Office).

4. <u>Assistant Accounts Officer in Sanowara Group of Company at SDBIL (September 2011 – August 2012)</u>

Sanowara Drinks & Beverage Industries Limited.

Location: Sylhet Depot Office Address: Amberkhana, Sylhet. Department: Accounts & Finance

Reporting to: Chief Accountant (Factory).

5. Administrative Assistant-HR and Accounts (May 2010-March 2011)

Unilever Bangladesh Limited

Location: Corporate Office Address: Gulshan-1, Dhaka. Department: Human Resource Reporting to: Manager (OSM).

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

National Unive Year of Passing: 2011	ersity	Masters in Accounting(M.Com) Major in Accounting Result: 1 st Class	
National Un Year of Passing: 2007	iiversity	Bachelor Of Commerce (B.Com) Result: 2nd Class	
Chittagong Year of Passing: 2001	Board	H.S.C. Group: Business Studies Result: 2nd Division	
Chittagong Year of Passing: 1999	Board	S.S.C. Group: Business Studies Result: 1st Division	

PROFESSIONAL LITERACY:

Course : CIMA.

Level : Professional Level

COMPUTER LITERACY:

: Microsoft Office Package. Application Software

Accounting Package : Skill with Customized ERP

environment specially Tally ERP 9, Troyee & Sysnet.

PERSONAL INFO:

Name : Md. Rezaul Islam

Father's name : Late Adv.Md. Shafiul Islam Mother's name : Selima Jinufa Khanam : October 16, 1983 Date of birth

Permanent address : Village – North Salimpur, PO.-Jafarabad, PS.-Shittakunda,

Chittagong, Bangladesh.

Marital Status : Single Religion : Islam Nationality : Bangladeshi National ID NO : 1518666159596

LANGUAGE SKILL:

: Working knowledge in English & Bengali.

REFERENCES:

ii

i. Md. Tarequl Islam Assistant Finance Manager Unilever Bangladesh Limited. Kalurghat BSCIC I/A,, Chittagong Cell: +88-01718-463783.

Director - Marketing.

Unity Corporation (Bangladesh) Ltd.

Majhirghat, Kotowali.

Mr. Tutul Dev

Cell: +88-01672-989481, +88-01633-757575

I hereby declared that all above information furnished by me is true.

(Md. Rezaul Islam)